<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine learning on Omanshu&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine learning on Omanshu&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:27:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MLP Approximation</title>
      <link>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/mlp-approximation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:27:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/mlp-approximation/</guid>
      <description>Almost always we hear about classification or machine learning problems, the go-to methods to solve the problem are neural networks, or multi-layered percetrons (MLP). Now function approximation problems, which is what classification is, are very well defined in terms of consistency, accuracy, and other abilities of the approximator. Why are MLPs then able to approximate functions well? Especially given the fact that most of the problems in coming up with candidate architectures, activation functions, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML SoTA Resources</title>
      <link>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/ml-sota/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 22:36:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/ml-sota/</guid>
      <description>The internet is filled with machine learning resources, and one of the most annoying things about them is the sheer volume. There are many attempts at making compilations of papers, code, and current status quo in the vastly active, and fast paced field. This post is to serve as a collection of my own where I will only post state of the art in machine learning.
Most of these links are updated frequently and maintained by the community, and I have collected these only for reference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>