<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Omanshu&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Omanshu&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 16:02:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Instrumentals v/s Vocal Music</title>
      <link>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/instrumental/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 16:02:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/instrumental/</guid>
      <description>I often talk to friends about music and musical preferences. This post is inspired by one such theme which often finds its way in most of these conversations: instrumental music v/s vocal music. Or more precisely, why listen to instrumental, or plain music, when you can have vocals accompanying the music.
This post is not from a musical perspective, but rather to emphasize on the entirely separate form of beauty inherent in instrumental music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compactness</title>
      <link>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/compactness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 07:58:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/compactness/</guid>
      <description>This is a non-mathematical note on what I understand about compactness and what it means for a set or a space to be compact. The open cover definition is one that can be found in any textbook, but what does it mean for a set to be compact? Why are such sets called compact? And how do compact sets differ from those which are not?
I think the terminology here is very carefully chosen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Point Estimate</title>
      <link>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/pointestimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 07:58:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://omanshuthapliyal.github.io/blog/posts/pointestimate/</guid>
      <description>This is going to take some time and effort to read, as it took to write; but I’ll try to answer to my best knowledge. I will follow a standard approach, but any terms that require some prior knowledge would contain wiki links.
##Background
MAP (maximum a priori estimate), MLE (maximum likelihood estimate) and MoM (method of moments) in this context refer to point estimation problems and are among many other estimation methods in statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>